[
    {
        "question": "1. What do you know about Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce has become a leader in CRM development. It is a single, integrated customer relationship management (CRM) platform that connects businesses with their customers. Salesforce provides a standard shared picture of every customer to all the departments, including marketing, sales, commerce, and service, and also allows users to store the data on a secure Cloud. Not only does the platform include a number of services and tools for relationship management, but it also assists in app development. As a result, Salesforce allows you to operate your business from anywhere.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Explain Salesforce Admin characteristics.",
        "answer": "Salesforce Administrators manage and maintain the Salesforce platform, making them an integral part of an organization’s technology team.\nSuccessful Salesforce Administrators possess technical proficiency, analytical skills, effective communication, problem-solving skills, attention to detail, and a commitment to continuous learning.\nThey use data to make informed decisions that optimize the platform’s performance and drive business success.\nSalesforce Administrators troubleshoot and solve problems related to the platform and ensure that the data is accurate and up-to-date, as it forms the basis for critical business decisions. They collaborate effectively with different teams and explain technical concepts in simple terms.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Expand and explain CRM.",
        "answer": "The expansion of CRM is ‘Customer Relationship Management.’\nCRM is an application that helps automate systems or digitize marketing functions. With this software, companies can plan to increase their profits and revenues. This strategy of incrementing revenue and profit is made by attracting customers, clients, and sales. The important concept of CRM is customer value.\nThere are four CRM initiatives as below:\nCustomer acquisition\nCustomer retention\nCustomer churn\nCustomer win-back",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Distinguish between Salesforce.com and Force.com.",
        "answer": "Both are relatively the same but different in their functionality.\nSalesforce.com helps build CRM-functionality-based applications, e.g., an iPhone ‘app’ that stores contact details, makes phone calls, and has all the other standard functions of a phone.\nForce.com is used to customize a data model and a user interface, e.g., an iPhone OS environment that can build and run apps.\nCheck out this insightful Salesforce Tutorial to learn more about Salesforce!\nInterested to know how much knowledge you have about customer management\nTake a quick Quiz to check it out\nTake a Quiz",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the available portals in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Three types of portals are available on Salesforce.com:\nCustomer portal: It enables us to utilize the capabilities of the web as the ideal channel to deliver superior self-service.\nPartner portal: It allows partner users to log in to Salesforce via a separate website than that is used by non-partner users.\nSelf-service portal: Customers will be able to search for details about the organization using this portal.\nFrom Intellipaat’s Salesforce Course in London, get a clear understanding of Salesforce!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Why do we use Tabs in Salesforce? Mention the types of Tabs.",
        "answer": "In Salesforce.com, a list of tabs is placed in the Tab menu. Tabs are used to access an object’s data.\nThere are three types of tabs:\nCustom tab\nVisualforce tab\nWeb tab\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now !\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy\n\nIntermediate Salesforce Admin Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is Profile? Mention the types of Profiles available in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "A profile is similar to settings and permissions in Salesforce. It is used to perform different functions that are defined by users. The profile serves as another way to manage particular records.\nThere are two types of profiles, which are enumerated below:\nStandard profiles: Profiles created by Force.com\nCustom profiles: Profiles created by users\nSalesforce standard profiles are:\nStandard User\nSolution Manager\nMarketing User\nRead-only\nSystem Administrator\nPreparing for a Salesforce Interview! Check out our Salesforce Interview Questions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is the difference between Profile and Role?",
        "answer": "The difference between Salesforce Profiles and Salesforce Roles are –\nProfiles: Object and field-level access may be created using profiles, such as general permissions, tab-level permissions, read & write permissions, and so on.\nRole: We may offer record-level access using roles, such as organization-wide defaults, Role hierarchy, sharing rules, and manual sharing. Simply put, record-level access is influenced by responsibilities.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. How to delete or freeze users in Salesforce.com?",
        "answer": "Deleting a user is not possible in Salesforce.com, but we can deactivate the user by using the Freeze option.\nTo freeze a user, go to:\nSetup > Manage Users > Users\nFind and click on the user, and then click on Freeze\nCheck out our blog on Salesforce Administrator Roles and Responsibilities!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Mention the ways to store files, documents, and images in Salesforce.com.",
        "answer": "We can store files, documents, and images in Salesforce.com as below:\nAttachments\nDocuments\nGoogle Drive\nLibraries\nChatter Files",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are the default index fields?",
        "answer": "Salesforce’s default indexed fields are:\nPrimary Keys: Name, ID, and owner fields)\nForeign Keys:  Lookup and Master-Detail Relationship Field\nAudit Dates: LastModifiesDate and SystemModstamp\nCustom Fields (only marked as External ID or unique)",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Give one-word answers to the following questions.",
        "answer": "a. On the Visualforce page, how many field dependencies are used?\nb. Can two users have the same profile in Salesforce?\nc. Which field cannot be added as a custom index?\nd. Can we edit a formula field value in a record?\ne. Can we use sharing rules to restrict data access?\na.10 field dependencies\nb.Yes.\nc.Formula field\nd. No.\ne. No.\nNow, you are aware of the benefits of Salesforce. For more, enroll in the Salesforce Course now!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "13.What is Field Dependency?",
        "answer": "In Salesforce, Field Dependencies are filters that will let the users modify their content and control the value of one field dependent on the value of another. There are two other fields in Field dependency which are.\nControlling Field.\nDependent field.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. How to set the Login Hours and Login IP ranges for the users in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Login Hours: If Login Hours is set in an organization, then it restricts the login before or after login hours.\nSetup | Administration | Manage users | Profiles\nLogin IP: It helps restrict login attempts from unauthorized IP addresses.\nSetup | Administration setup | Manage users | Profiles",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Mention various types of sharing rules in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "There are a few sharing rules in Salesforce available which are as follows:\nAccount sharing Rule.\nCase Sharing Rule.\nContact Sharing Rule.\nCustom Object sharing Rule.\nLead Sharing Rule.\nOpportunity sharing Rule.\nWant to learn about Salesforce Architecture? Check out our tutorial on the Architecture of Salesforce.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. List the characteristics and functions of a Roll-up Summary field.",
        "answer": "Characteristics of a roll-up summary field:\nIt can be created for a Master-Detail relationship but not for a Lookup relationship.\nAuto numbers are not available here.\nWe cannot change the field type in a roll-up summary field.\nIt derives data from the Child object.\nThe functions of the roll-up summary field are mentioned as follows:\nCount\nSum\nMin\nMax",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What are the different kinds of Reports in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Different kinds of reports in Salesforce are:\nTabular Report: It is similar to a spreadsheet and is the simplest and fastest way to see data. Tabular reports are the best to create lists of records.\nSummary Report: It is similar to a tabular report but allows users to group rows of data, view subtotals, and create charts.\nMatrix Report: It is similar to a summary report, but it allows users to group and summarize data by both rows and columns.\nJoined Report: Joined reports let us create multiple report blocks that provide different views of our data and each block acts as a subreport.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. Mention the ways to share a record.",
        "answer": "In Salesforce, there are 5 ways we can share records\nRole Hierarchy\nOrganization Wide Defaults\nManual Sharing\nCriteria-Based Sharing Rules\nApex Sharing",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. Do you know about Bucket fields in Salesforce reports?",
        "answer": "Without the need for any sophisticated algorithms or custom fields, a bucket field allows you to combine related data together by ranges and segments. Bucketing is a method of grouping, filtering, and arranging report data. You must define numerous categories (buckets) that are used to group report values when creating a bucket field.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Watch the below Salesforce Admin tutorial to learn more:",
        "answer": "",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Define Dynamic Dashboards. Can we schedule Dynamic Dashboards?",
        "answer": "Dynamic dashboards help us display the set of metrics in an organization. They are created to provide security settings for dashboards at Salesforce.com.\nTwo setting options are there in dynamic dashboards:\nRun as a specified user\nRun as the logged-in user\nLearn more about Salesforce from this Salesforce Training in New York to get ahead in your career!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. What is Workflow in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Workflow in Salesforce is business logic that helps you to automate your organization’s normal processes and procedures, saving you a significant amount of time. Workflow allows records to carry out tasks like changing data or notifying individuals or external systems. We can automate tasks like assigning tasks, sending emails, updating fields, and sending outbound messages.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Name the different Workflow components in Salesforce.com.",
        "answer": "There are five workflow components in Salesforce.com:\nWorkflow Rules\nWorkflow Tasks\nWorkflow Email Alerts\nWorkflow Field Updates\nWorkflow Outbound Messages\nInterested in learning Salesforce? Learn more from our Salesforce Training in Sydney!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. What are the various types of relationships available in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "There are the various relationship types in Salesforce that users can create. Which are:\nSelf-relationship\nLookup\nIndirect lookup\nExternal lookup\nMany-to-many (junction object)\nHierarchical\nMaster-detail relationship",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. What are the limitations of a Time-dependent Workflow?",
        "answer": "Limitations of a time-dependent workflow are as follows:\nTime triggers do not support minutes or seconds.\nTime triggers cannot reference when formula fields that include related-object merge fields.\nWe cannot add or remove a time trigger if:\nThe workflow rule is active\nThe workflow rule is included in the package\nVisit Salesforce Community and get all your queries resolved!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. Mention some CRM providers",
        "answer": "The popular CRM providers are:\nOracle CRM\nMicrosoft Dynamics CRM\nSalesforce CRM\nSAP CRM\nNetSuite CRM\nSage CRM\nSugarCRM",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. Who can access the drag-and-drop dashboard?",
        "answer": "The one who has in managed dashboards can access the drag-and-drop dashboard",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. How many ways are there to call an Apex class?",
        "answer": "There are four ways to call an Apex class:\nVisual page\nWeb service\nTriggers\nEmail services\nBecome a master of Salesforce by going through this online Salesforce Course in Toronto!\n\nAdvanced Salesforce Admin Interview Questions and Answers for Experienced Professionals",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. What is the Formula field?",
        "answer": "A Formula field is a read-only field that is coupled with a formula or expression from which its value is calculated. With the corresponding modification in the formula or expression, the value of this type of field is immediately changed. This field can be created using both standard and custom objects.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. How to insert multiple records at a time?",
        "answer": "public class insert50{\npublic void p1(){\nList<Example_c> IstTesting = new List<Example_c>();\nIstTesing.add(new Example_c(Name='Example1', City_c='City1'));\nIstTesing.add(new Example_c(Name='Example2', City_c='City2'));\nIstTesing.add(new Example_c(Name='Example3', City_c='City3'));\ninsert lstTesting;\n}\n}",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. What is Data Loader?",
        "answer": "Salesforce Data Loader is a client application that allows you to import or export data in bulk. One can insert, update, remove, or export Salesforce records with this tool. Data Loader reads, extracts, and loads data from comma-separated values (CSV) files or a database connection for importing data. It creates CSV files for exporting data.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. When do we use Data Loader?",
        "answer": "We use a data loader for the following situations:\nWhen we need to insert, update, delete, or upsert large volumes of records in Salesforce (more than 50,000 records).\nWhen you need to load data into an object that is not yet supported by web-based importing, such as the Chatter free data license object or custom objects with complex relationships.\nWhen you want to save multiple mapping files for future use or share them with other users.\nWhen you want to export data from Salesforce for backup or migration purposes.\nWhen you want to prevent duplicates by uploading records with a unique external ID field.\nGet certified by the top Salesforce Course in Singapore now!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. What are the Data management tools in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "There are two data management tools available in Salesforce which are:\nData Import Wizard\nData Loader",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. Define SaaS.",
        "answer": "In Software as a Service (SaaS), the cloud service provides software that we need to develop an application, saving us from purchasing it. SaaS supports web services and service-oriented architecture.\nTop SaaS providers are:\nAbiquo\nAccelOps\nAkamai\nAppDynamics\nApprenda\nLearn complete concepts of Salesforce from this Salesforce Training at Hyderabad in just 24 hours!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. Define PaaS.",
        "answer": "In Platform as a Service (PaaS), the cloud service provides an operating system (OS), hardware, storage, and network services through the cloud, but we have to pay the service providers based on our subscription, like the rental services.\nTop PaaS providers are:\nAWS Elastic Beanstalk\nAppScale\nAppistry (Cloud)\nCA Technologies\nEngine Yard",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. Define IaaS.",
        "answer": "In Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), the cloud service provides the infrastructure, such as servers, hosting service, and storage.\nTop IaaS providers are:\nAWS\nAT&T\nCA Technologies\nCloudscaling\nBluelock\nEucalyptus\nAre you interested in learning Salesforce from experts? Enroll in our Salesforce Course in Bangalore today!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. What are the different Salesforce editions?",
        "answer": "Essentials: The Salesforce Essentials edition is specially designed for small-scale businesses. It consists of an easy-to-use UI. There are various salesforce tools in the edition that help customize it according to business needs.\nProfessional: This edition is built for businesses that require the most CRM functionality. It has features such as easy customization and integration with other technologies. Also, it consists of administration tools that help in the deployment of a small-scale application.\nEnterprise: The Enterprise edition is built for large-scale businesses. It provides advanced customization tools. The administration tools of the Enterprise edition helps large-scale deployment. The edition allows access to the features of the Salesforce API.\nUnlimited: This edition consists of extremely advanced features that help maximize usage. The Unlimited edition of Salesforce allows for the efficient management of business resources that can be provided instantly on demand. Also, it provides premier support, high storage limit, an increased number of custom apps, and many more features.\nDeveloper: The Developer edition gives access to APIs and the Salesforce Lightning Platform. It provides tools that allow developers to customize the Salesforce platform and integrate it with other technologies and applications. Also, the edition consists of those features that are present in the Enterprise edition.\nWant to know How much a Salesforce Developer makes? Check out our blog Salesforce Developer Salary.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. What are login hours and login IP ranges in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce Applications provide features such as login hours and login IP ranges.\nLogin hours: In an organization, the schedule for login and logout is set to define the time limit and working hours. It flags the user who does not follow the schedule. To set the login hours for an organization in a Salesforce platform, go to:\nSetup > Administration > Manage Users > Profiles\nLogin IP ranges: If a user tries to login via an unknown IP, then the organization is alerted, and it can restrict the user to do so. Organizations use IP ranges to maintain secure access so that they can prevent any kind of loss. For setting up the login IP ranges, go to:\nSetup > Administration Setup > Manage Users > Profiles",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "38. What is meant by TAB in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce tabs allow users to see information at a glance. In the program, it shows the data of objects and other web material.\nTypes of TAB in salesforce are:\nStandard object tabs\nCustom object tabs\nWeb tabs\nVisualforce tabs",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. What is field-level security and how can it be controlled?",
        "answer": "Field-level security helps control the accessibility of a user to a particular data field. Suppose, if an organization is providing a user with the access to see, edit, manipulate, or delete a data object specific to the user’s field of work, it can hide other data objects from the user.\nTo control the field-level security, we use to profile and permission sets. The attributes of profile and permission sets are mentioned below:\nProfiles\nPage layouts\nIP ranges\nLogin hours\nDesktop\nClient access\nPermission\nApp permissions\nRecord types\nTab settings\nAssigned apps\nObject permissions\nField-level security\nApex classes\nVisualforce pages\nAlso, Check out our blog to learn about Salesforce Automation System!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. What is a custom metadata type?",
        "answer": "The custom metadata type stores information about an organization. It is a type of custom object that can be customized, deployed, packaged, and upgraded. It helps use data for configuring the application without fretting about data migration. Rather than transferring the custom metadata type manually, it can be deployed using a Sandbox.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. What is the difference between managed and unmanaged packages?",
        "answer": "Attribute Managed Packages Unmanaged Packages\nCustomization The code or metadata cannot be changed If required, the code and metadata can be customized\nUpgrades The solution is upgraded by the provider For upgrading, we should replace the previous version with the new version\nOrg Limits There is no limit for the usage of apps, tabs, and objects The packages set limits for the usage of apps, tabs, and objects",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. How can we clear the time-based workflow action queue?",
        "answer": "There are two ways to clear a time-based workflow action queue:\nFirst, you can make false criteria.\nOr you can clear by removing actions that are rescheduled from the queue.\nCheck out our blog to learn about map class in salesforce!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. What is OWD and Do you know how many accesses are available in OWD?",
        "answer": "The default level of access to data records for all users in an organization is defined by the Organization’s defaults. Defaults are used to limit data access across the organization (Records). For both Standard and Custom Objects, Organization-Wide Defaults (OWD) can be set.\nIn Organization-Wide Default, around 13 various accesses are available. They are as follows:\nPublic Read Only.\nPublic Read/Write.\nPublic Read/Write/Transfer.\nPublic Full Access.\nPrivate\nView Only.\nUse\nHide Details.\nHide Details and Events.\nShow Details.\nShow Details and Events.\nControlled by parent\nNo Access.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. What is meant by an App in Salesforce? And what are the types of Apps?",
        "answer": "In Salesforce.org, an app serves as a container. There are tabs, a logo, and a name on them. It’s a collection of tabs that provide the Salesforce developer with the features he or she is seeking for. If you need to develop an app in Salesforce, simply follow the steps below:\nSetup ->Build ->Create->App-> Click on new\nSalesforce has two types of Apps which are:\nCustom App\nConsole App\nAlso, check out the blog on Salesforce Trailhead.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. How can we add JavaScript remoting to the Visualforce page?",
        "answer": "In order to add JavaScript remoting to your Visualforce page, we need to follow the syntax mentioned below:\n[namespace.]controller.method(\n[parameters]\nCallbackfunction,\n[configuration]\n);",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What is Salesforce Lightning?",
        "answer": "  'Lightning' (Salesforce Lightning) is Salesforce's component-based framework for application development, aimed at simplifying business processes for users with no or little programming experience. The Lightning Component Framework is part of Lightning, and some great tools are available for developers as well. With Lightning, you will be able to easily create responsive applications for any device.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. State difference between Salesforce admin and developer.",
        "answer": "The differences between Salesforce admins and developers are as follows: Salesforce Admin Salesforce Developer\nSalesforce administrators are responsible for ensuring that the Salesforce applications are properly installed and implemented in an organization. Salesforce developers, as the name suggests, are primarily involved in the development process of the application. \nSalesforce developers implement new implementation strategies to enable business improvements. It is, more or less, the responsibility of this individual to design and develop specific codes and functionality to create customized applications.\nRoles:\nGetting together with project managers to discuss CRM requirements.\nAssist with the design and development of Salesforce-based applications.\nCreating development timelines and goals.\nEvaluating the stability and functionality of the application.\nDeveloping APEX.\nDebugging the application.\nAssessing custom-developed code.\nRoles:\nAssessing business requirements and recommending the most effective solution.\nAssisting with upgrading the Salesforce system.\nIntegrate and configure the system continuously and effectively.\nAdministration of Salesforce profiles, roles, workflows, etc.\nAssist in preparing reports for team members, etc.\nMaintaining the database, including performing diagnostic tests and erasing duplicate entries.\nDocumentation of processes such as error reports and the updating of field history tables.\nAmong the top companies offering Salesforce administration jobs are Amazon, Expedia, Kaplan Financial, Main Street Hub, Magnetrol, Globoforce, AvidXchange, and many other companies.  Among the top companies offering Salesforce Developer jobs are Slalom Consulting, Accenture, Crossmark, Amazon.com Inc, Accenture technology solutions, Cognizant, and many other companies. Salesforce Admin Salesforce Developer\nSalesforce administrators are responsible for ensuring that the Salesforce applications are properly installed and implemented in an organization. Salesforce developers, as the name suggests, are primarily involved in the development process of the application. \nSalesforce developers implement new implementation strategies to enable business improvements. It is, more or less, the responsibility of this individual to design and develop specific codes and functionality to create customized applications.\nRoles:\nGetting together with project managers to discuss CRM requirements.\nAssist with the design and development of Salesforce-based applications.\nCreating development timelines and goals.\nEvaluating the stability and functionality of the application.\nDeveloping APEX.\nDebugging the application.\nAssessing custom-developed code.\nRoles:\nAssessing business requirements and recommending the most effective solution.\nAssisting with upgrading the Salesforce system.\nIntegrate and configure the system continuously and effectively.\nAdministration of Salesforce profiles, roles, workflows, etc.\nAssist in preparing reports for team members, etc.\nMaintaining the database, including performing diagnostic tests and erasing duplicate entries.\nDocumentation of processes such as error reports and the updating of field history tables.\nAmong the top companies offering Salesforce administration jobs are Amazon, Expedia, Kaplan Financial, Main Street Hub, Magnetrol, Globoforce, AvidXchange, and many other companies.  Among the top companies offering Salesforce Developer jobs are Slalom Consulting, Accenture, Crossmark, Amazon.com Inc, Accenture technology solutions, Cognizant, and many other companies. Salesforce Admin Salesforce Developer Salesforce Admin Salesforce Developer Salesforce Admin Salesforce Developer Salesforce administrators are responsible for ensuring that the Salesforce applications are properly installed and implemented in an organization. Salesforce developers, as the name suggests, are primarily involved in the development process of the application. \nSalesforce developers implement new implementation strategies to enable business improvements. It is, more or less, the responsibility of this individual to design and develop specific codes and functionality to create customized applications.\nRoles:\nGetting together with project managers to discuss CRM requirements.\nAssist with the design and development of Salesforce-based applications.\nCreating development timelines and goals.\nEvaluating the stability and functionality of the application.\nDeveloping APEX.\nDebugging the application.\nAssessing custom-developed code.\nRoles:\nAssessing business requirements and recommending the most effective solution.\nAssisting with upgrading the Salesforce system.\nIntegrate and configure the system continuously and effectively.\nAdministration of Salesforce profiles, roles, workflows, etc.\nAssist in preparing reports for team members, etc.\nMaintaining the database, including performing diagnostic tests and erasing duplicate entries.\nDocumentation of processes such as error reports and the updating of field history tables.\nAmong the top companies offering Salesforce administration jobs are Amazon, Expedia, Kaplan Financial, Main Street Hub, Magnetrol, Globoforce, AvidXchange, and many other companies.  Among the top companies offering Salesforce Developer jobs are Slalom Consulting, Accenture, Crossmark, Amazon.com Inc, Accenture technology solutions, Cognizant, and many other companies. Salesforce administrators are responsible for ensuring that the Salesforce applications are properly installed and implemented in an organization. Salesforce developers, as the name suggests, are primarily involved in the development process of the application. Salesforce administrators are responsible for ensuring that the Salesforce applications are properly installed and implemented in an organization. Salesforce developers, as the name suggests, are primarily involved in the development process of the application. Salesforce developers implement new implementation strategies to enable business improvements. It is, more or less, the responsibility of this individual to design and develop specific codes and functionality to create customized applications. Salesforce developers implement new implementation strategies to enable business improvements. It is, more or less, the responsibility of this individual to design and develop specific codes and functionality to create customized applications. Roles:\nGetting together with project managers to discuss CRM requirements.\nAssist with the design and development of Salesforce-based applications.\nCreating development timelines and goals.\nEvaluating the stability and functionality of the application.\nDeveloping APEX.\nDebugging the application.\nAssessing custom-developed code.\nRoles:\nAssessing business requirements and recommending the most effective solution.\nAssisting with upgrading the Salesforce system.\nIntegrate and configure the system continuously and effectively.\nAdministration of Salesforce profiles, roles, workflows, etc.\nAssist in preparing reports for team members, etc.\nMaintaining the database, including performing diagnostic tests and erasing duplicate entries.\nDocumentation of processes such as error reports and the updating of field history tables. Roles:\nGetting together with project managers to discuss CRM requirements.\nAssist with the design and development of Salesforce-based applications.\nCreating development timelines and goals.\nEvaluating the stability and functionality of the application.\nDeveloping APEX.\nDebugging the application.\nAssessing custom-developed code. Roles: Getting together with project managers to discuss CRM requirements.\nAssist with the design and development of Salesforce-based applications.\nCreating development timelines and goals.\nEvaluating the stability and functionality of the application.\nDeveloping APEX.\nDebugging the application.\nAssessing custom-developed code. Getting together with project managers to discuss CRM requirements. Assist with the design and development of Salesforce-based applications. Creating development timelines and goals. Evaluating the stability and functionality of the application. Developing APEX. Debugging the application. Assessing custom-developed code. Roles:\nAssessing business requirements and recommending the most effective solution.\nAssisting with upgrading the Salesforce system.\nIntegrate and configure the system continuously and effectively.\nAdministration of Salesforce profiles, roles, workflows, etc.\nAssist in preparing reports for team members, etc.\nMaintaining the database, including performing diagnostic tests and erasing duplicate entries.\nDocumentation of processes such as error reports and the updating of field history tables. Roles: Assessing business requirements and recommending the most effective solution.\nAssisting with upgrading the Salesforce system.\nIntegrate and configure the system continuously and effectively.\nAdministration of Salesforce profiles, roles, workflows, etc.\nAssist in preparing reports for team members, etc.\nMaintaining the database, including performing diagnostic tests and erasing duplicate entries.\nDocumentation of processes such as error reports and the updating of field history tables. Assessing business requirements and recommending the most effective solution. Assisting with upgrading the Salesforce system. Integrate and configure the system continuously and effectively. Administration of Salesforce profiles, roles, workflows, etc. Assist in preparing reports for team members, etc. Maintaining the database, including performing diagnostic tests and erasing duplicate entries. Documentation of processes such as error reports and the updating of field history tables. Among the top companies offering Salesforce administration jobs are Amazon, Expedia, Kaplan Financial, Main Street Hub, Magnetrol, Globoforce, AvidXchange, and many other companies.  Among the top companies offering Salesforce Developer jobs are Slalom Consulting, Accenture, Crossmark, Amazon.com Inc, Accenture technology solutions, Cognizant, and many other companies. Among the top companies offering Salesforce administration jobs are Amazon, Expedia, Kaplan Financial, Main Street Hub, Magnetrol, Globoforce, AvidXchange, and many other companies. Among the top companies offering Salesforce Developer jobs are Slalom Consulting, Accenture, Crossmark, Amazon.com Inc, Accenture technology solutions, Cognizant, and many other companies.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is Salesforce Admin?",
        "answer": "A Salesforce administrator is an individual who specializes in the Salesforce CRM (Customer Relationship Management) system and the products that it provides. It is their responsibility to administer Salesforce systems, train staff on Salesforce products, and maintain sales databases. Simply put, the Salesforce admin allows users to leverage the Salesforce platform in the most productive way possible. It is a Salesforce Admin who truly understands how to configure the platform to achieve the company's goals.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are Salesforce reports?",
        "answer": "As part of the management process, the reports are used to track progress towards the company's various goals, control its expenditures, as well as increase its revenues. Reports play a crucial role in forecasting trends and can therefore increase profits. Reports can be created in Salesforce.com in a variety of ways and can be scheduled as well. You can organize, view, and analyze your data with Salesforce's suite of analytic tools.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the different types of report formats in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Report formats in Salesforce can be classified into four different types as follows: Tabular Reports: This is the most basic of all report formats and it simply displays the records in a table without a grand total. Tabular reports are ideal for when you need a simple list or a list of items without a grand total.\nSummary Reports: As the name implies, this type of report displays a listing of data with groupings and subtotals at the bottom.\nMatrix Reports: Unlike other types of reports, this one gives you the option to group records both by row and by column. Furthermore, this report can be used to generate dashboards as well.\nJoined Reports: These types of reports allow us to create different views of the data from the different types of reports. In a joined report, the data are organized into blocks. Each block is a sub-report containing its columns, own fields, sorting, and filtering. Tabular Reports: This is the most basic of all report formats and it simply displays the records in a table without a grand total. Tabular reports are ideal for when you need a simple list or a list of items without a grand total. Tabular Reports: Summary Reports: As the name implies, this type of report displays a listing of data with groupings and subtotals at the bottom. Summary Reports: Matrix Reports: Unlike other types of reports, this one gives you the option to group records both by row and by column. Furthermore, this report can be used to generate dashboards as well. Matrix Reports: Joined Reports: These types of reports allow us to create different views of the data from the different types of reports. In a joined report, the data are organized into blocks. Each block is a sub-report containing its columns, own fields, sorting, and filtering. Joined Reports:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. State difference between profile and role in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "Profiles and roles are both used to maintain security and permissions within the system.   Profile Role\nIn a nutshell, we can think of them as profiles that dictate what the user can do with specific objects.  A role in Salesforce is a specific access level that defines how an individual has access to a record based on their role. \nBased on their profile, you will be able to grant the user permission to do whichever of these actions (create/read/edit/delete) they choose. Roles can be used as a means of specifying the level of access that a user can have to the data within an organization. As simple as it may sound, it defines what a Salesforce user is permitted to access within an organization.\nThere are several Salesforce profile controls that you can set, for instance, the total number of plugin hours, IP address details for the login, application settings, record types, field permissions, page layouts, etc. Roles control the hierarchy of record access privileges a client has, extend the OWD (Organization-Wide Default) settings for various objects and share principles for sharing records with specific roles. Profile Role\nIn a nutshell, we can think of them as profiles that dictate what the user can do with specific objects.  A role in Salesforce is a specific access level that defines how an individual has access to a record based on their role. \nBased on their profile, you will be able to grant the user permission to do whichever of these actions (create/read/edit/delete) they choose. Roles can be used as a means of specifying the level of access that a user can have to the data within an organization. As simple as it may sound, it defines what a Salesforce user is permitted to access within an organization.\nThere are several Salesforce profile controls that you can set, for instance, the total number of plugin hours, IP address details for the login, application settings, record types, field permissions, page layouts, etc. Roles control the hierarchy of record access privileges a client has, extend the OWD (Organization-Wide Default) settings for various objects and share principles for sharing records with specific roles. Profile Role Profile Role Profile Role In a nutshell, we can think of them as profiles that dictate what the user can do with specific objects.  A role in Salesforce is a specific access level that defines how an individual has access to a record based on their role. \nBased on their profile, you will be able to grant the user permission to do whichever of these actions (create/read/edit/delete) they choose. Roles can be used as a means of specifying the level of access that a user can have to the data within an organization. As simple as it may sound, it defines what a Salesforce user is permitted to access within an organization.\nThere are several Salesforce profile controls that you can set, for instance, the total number of plugin hours, IP address details for the login, application settings, record types, field permissions, page layouts, etc. Roles control the hierarchy of record access privileges a client has, extend the OWD (Organization-Wide Default) settings for various objects and share principles for sharing records with specific roles. In a nutshell, we can think of them as profiles that dictate what the user can do with specific objects.  A role in Salesforce is a specific access level that defines how an individual has access to a record based on their role. In a nutshell, we can think of them as profiles that dictate what the user can do with specific objects. A role in Salesforce is a specific access level that defines how an individual has access to a record based on their role. Based on their profile, you will be able to grant the user permission to do whichever of these actions (create/read/edit/delete) they choose. Roles can be used as a means of specifying the level of access that a user can have to the data within an organization. As simple as it may sound, it defines what a Salesforce user is permitted to access within an organization. Based on their profile, you will be able to grant the user permission to do whichever of these actions (create/read/edit/delete) they choose. Roles can be used as a means of specifying the level of access that a user can have to the data within an organization. As simple as it may sound, it defines what a Salesforce user is permitted to access within an organization. There are several Salesforce profile controls that you can set, for instance, the total number of plugin hours, IP address details for the login, application settings, record types, field permissions, page layouts, etc. Roles control the hierarchy of record access privileges a client has, extend the OWD (Organization-Wide Default) settings for various objects and share principles for sharing records with specific roles. There are several Salesforce profile controls that you can set, for instance, the total number of plugin hours, IP address details for the login, application settings, record types, field permissions, page layouts, etc. Roles control the hierarchy of record access privileges a client has, extend the OWD (Organization-Wide Default) settings for various objects and share principles for sharing records with specific roles.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is Apex?",
        "answer": "Apex is an object-oriented programming language that enables developers to execute necessary flow and transactional control commands on the Lightning Platform server, along with any API calls. By using syntax that looks and acts just like Java and as if it were a stored procedure, Apex is a business logic extension to Salesforce that lets developers provide logic to many system instances, including record updates, button clicks, and visual force pages. Moreover, it is used to develop SaaS (Software as a Service) applications on top of Salesforce CRM functionality.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Explain Database.com.",
        "answer": "Database.com is the primary enterprise database storage platform for Salesforce, and Salesforce data is stored in the cloud via this platform. The database.com product is a vast data storage facility that allows users to safely store millions of records, retrieve them for use in developing apps, and create flawless transactions in a fraction of a second. Database.com provides a powerful cloud infrastructure that provides a means to efficiently store, retrieve, and manipulate information. Listed below are some of the valuable features that Database.com provides: It offers storage space for images, videos, and documents.\nProvides relational data capabilities, such as tables, fields, triggers, queries, relationships, and search capabilities.\nProvides user management functionality.\nImproved enterprise search engine services and security rules to ensure that the data remains secure. It offers storage space for images, videos, and documents. Provides relational data capabilities, such as tables, fields, triggers, queries, relationships, and search capabilities. Provides user management functionality. Improved enterprise search engine services and security rules to ensure that the data remains secure.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What do you mean by page layout and record types?",
        "answer": "  Page Layout: With Page Layouts, Salesforce allows you to control how Salesforce pages are arranged and displayed. You may be able to control the positioning of fields, Buttons, Custom links, S-controls, Visualforce, and related lists on any of the object record pages. Also, page layouts determine which fields on object record pages are marked as read-only, visible, or required.\nRecord Types: Records types allow you to display different processes, picklist values, and object layouts to different Salesforce users. The record type offers many benefits, however, if it is not implemented correctly, it can result in added complexity for users and administrators. Page Layout: With Page Layouts, Salesforce allows you to control how Salesforce pages are arranged and displayed. You may be able to control the positioning of fields, Buttons, Custom links, S-controls, Visualforce, and related lists on any of the object record pages. Also, page layouts determine which fields on object record pages are marked as read-only, visible, or required. Page Layout: Record Types: Records types allow you to display different processes, picklist values, and object layouts to different Salesforce users. The record type offers many benefits, however, if it is not implemented correctly, it can result in added complexity for users and administrators. Record Types:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. In what ways are files, images, and documents stored in Salesforce.com? List them out.",
        "answer": "Salesforce.com allows us to store files, images, and documents in the following ways: Attachments\nDocuments\nGoogle Drive\nLibraries\nChatter Files Attachments Documents Google Drive Libraries Chatter Files",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What is Salesforce Chatter?",
        "answer": "Chatter is a Salesforce application that makes it easy for your users to communicate, collaborate, and share information in real-time. Chatter can be used by individuals of all roles and locations in the organization to connect, engage, and motivate them to work efficiently.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Explain the Approval process.",
        "answer": "Approval processes are types of workflows that require work to pass through a series of steps to be approved. This process typically involves reviewing the work and approving or rejecting it by various departments with employees from different positions involved in the process. After this, the workflows in both directions, either back to the previous step for editing, or on to the next step for further approval, depending on whether the work has been accepted or rejected by one department. Currently, many companies use computers to automate their approval processes, however, some firms still use manual approval procedures, such as passing paper documents from department to department.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What do you mean by time-dependent workflow? Write its limitations.",
        "answer": "When working on a real-time project, there are some situations where we do not need to execute the task immediately. Time-dependent actions can help in these cases. Time-dependent actions are performed at a specific time, such as 10 hours or 10 days  (time triggers) before the closing date of a record. The workflow rule evaluates the record after that period has passed to ensure that it still meets the rules. If so, the workflow rule performs those actions. In Salesforce, a time trigger indicates after how many hours or days we want this action to be performed. Limitations Limitations Minutes and seconds are not supported by time triggers.\nA time trigger cannot be added or removed if:\nThe workflow rule is currently active.\nThe package includes the workflow rule. Minutes and seconds are not supported by time triggers. A time trigger cannot be added or removed if:\nThe workflow rule is currently active.\nThe package includes the workflow rule. The workflow rule is currently active.\nThe package includes the workflow rule. The workflow rule is currently active. The package includes the workflow rule.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What are the various workflow actions available in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce offers the following workflow actions: Task: It is a simple way of assigning a task to an individual user, a team member, or a role. The assignee can be notified via email when a task is automatically assigned.\nEmail Alert: It uses an email template to send automated email messages. Salesforce allows users to create an email template that can be used to send emails when they need to.\nField update: Field updates are used to automatically change the value of a field on a record that was initially triggered by the workflow rule.\nOutbound Message: Outbound messages are those that are sent to a designated endpoint, such as an external service. Listening to these types of messages is possible using a SOAP (Standard Communication Protocol System) API. Task: It is a simple way of assigning a task to an individual user, a team member, or a role. The assignee can be notified via email when a task is automatically assigned. Task: Email Alert: It uses an email template to send automated email messages. Salesforce allows users to create an email template that can be used to send emails when they need to. Email Alert: Field update: Field updates are used to automatically change the value of a field on a record that was initially triggered by the workflow rule. Field update: Outbound Message: Outbound messages are those that are sent to a designated endpoint, such as an external service. Listening to these types of messages is possible using a SOAP (Standard Communication Protocol System) API. Outbound Message:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Mention how we can share a record.",
        "answer": "A record can be shared in five different ways, as follows: Manual Sharing.\nApex Sharing.\nRole Hierarchy.\nCriteria Based Sharing Rules.\nOrganization-Wide Defaults (OWD). Manual Sharing. Apex Sharing. Role Hierarchy. Criteria Based Sharing Rules. Organization-Wide Defaults (OWD).",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Explain the permission set in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Permission sets are essentially collections of settings and permissions that allow users access to certain features and tools. In other words, permission sets can extend the functional access of users without modifying their profiles. A Salesforce user can only have one profile, although depending on the Salesforce edition, they may have several permission sets. Permission sets may be assigned to various types of users regardless of their profile.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What are the different types of relationships in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "In Salesforce, it is possible to establish a relationship between objects. It is possible to associate objects with one another. The following are a few types of relationships that can be established between objects: Master-detail relationship: Salesforce objects are strongly coupled, so deleting a master record also deletes the child records associated with it. Typically, the parent record controls the visibility and sharing of the child record. The security settings of a parent object apply to its child.\nLookup relationship: Loosely coupled relationships between Salesforce objects mean that even if the parent object is deleted, the child object will remain in the system. In this case, both the child and the parent have separate sharing settings and security controls.\nSelf-relationship: One example of a look-up relationship would be a self-relationship. Salesforce allows us to create self-relationships between objects using lookup relationships; we can have up to 40 self-relationships between Salesforce objects.\nExternal lookup relationship: It lets us link or connect an external object to a parent external object whose data resides in an external database. In simple words, we connect two external objects.\nIndirect lookup relationship: With an indirect lookup relationship, we can link a standard or custom object to an external object.\nMany-to-many relationship (junction object): Many-to-many relationships in Salesforce allow us to link a child record with multiple parents. Master-detail relationship: Salesforce objects are strongly coupled, so deleting a master record also deletes the child records associated with it. Typically, the parent record controls the visibility and sharing of the child record. The security settings of a parent object apply to its child. Master-detail relationship: Lookup relationship: Loosely coupled relationships between Salesforce objects mean that even if the parent object is deleted, the child object will remain in the system. In this case, both the child and the parent have separate sharing settings and security controls. Lookup relationship: Self-relationship: One example of a look-up relationship would be a self-relationship. Salesforce allows us to create self-relationships between objects using lookup relationships; we can have up to 40 self-relationships between Salesforce objects. Self-relationship: External lookup relationship: It lets us link or connect an external object to a parent external object whose data resides in an external database. In simple words, we connect two external objects. External lookup relationship: Indirect lookup relationship: With an indirect lookup relationship, we can link a standard or custom object to an external object. Indirect lookup relationship: Many-to-many relationship (junction object): Many-to-many relationships in Salesforce allow us to link a child record with multiple parents. Many-to-many relationship (junction object):",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are the Salesforce portals available?",
        "answer": "Salesforce portals can be classified into three types as follows: Self-Service Portal: Self-Service is a means of providing online support to your customers that enables them to resolve their issues without contacting customer service.\nPartner Portal: The Partner Portal is intended to provide support to your Partners. Partners are Salesforce users with restricted rights. They are tied to a specific partner account and have limited access to your organization's data.\nCustomer Portal: In pretty much the same way that a self-service portal does, the Customer Portal provides online support to your customers, allowing them to resolve their problems without having to contact customer service. Self-Service Portal: Self-Service is a means of providing online support to your customers that enables them to resolve their issues without contacting customer service. Self-Service Portal: Partner Portal: The Partner Portal is intended to provide support to your Partners. Partners are Salesforce users with restricted rights. They are tied to a specific partner account and have limited access to your organization's data. Partner Portal: Customer Portal: In pretty much the same way that a self-service portal does, the Customer Portal provides online support to your customers, allowing them to resolve their problems without having to contact customer service. Customer Portal:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Can you explain the bucket field in reports?",
        "answer": "Salesforce Reports includes a bucket field capability that enables you to categorize the values of any field in a report quickly and easily without the need to create a formula field at the object level. When multiple values of a field need to be categorized into a single category, Salesforce bucket fields are used.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What do you mean by conditional highlighting in Salesforce reports? Write its limitations.",
        "answer": "Conditional highlighting in Salesforce reports provides you with the ability to highlight field values on matrix and summary reports based on the colors and ranges you specify. For conditional highlighting to work, your report must include one or more summary fields or a custom summary formula. Limitations Limitations There can be a maximum of three conditions per report.\nConditional Highlighting is only applicable to the summary and matrix reports.\nOnly available for use in numerical analysis.\nFirst condition < second condition < third condition >=. There can be a maximum of three conditions per report. Conditional Highlighting is only applicable to the summary and matrix reports. Only available for use in numerical analysis. First condition < second condition < third condition >=.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are different Salesforce editions?",
        "answer": "Salesforce CRM offers a wide range of services and features, each tailored to address certain business needs. These bundles are called editions, and they share the same look and feel but differ in functionality and price. As business requirements evolve, many customers upgrade from a basic edition to a more feature-rich one. Below is a list of some Salesforce editions:   Essential Edition: Designed to give small businesses a quick and easy way to get started with a CRM system, this edition will give them everything they need. Its easy-to-use UI, intuitive tutorials, setup assistant, and administration tools will help you customize and scale your deployment over time.\nProfessional Edition: The Professional Edition is targeted at businesses that need full-featured CRM functionality to manage their operations. With Salesforce professional edition, businesses can conveniently manage their entire sales cycle from lead generation to close with ease.\nEnterprise Edition: With the Enterprise edition, organizations can automate their complex business processes using workflows and approvals in addition to the features offered by the Professional edition. There are various customization and management tools included in this edition of Symphony to support large-scale deployments.\nUnlimited Edition: A crucial feature of the Unlimited Edition is the ability to extend business success across the whole enterprise using the Lightning Platform so that the company can achieve maximum success. It offers all the features of the Enterprise edition and comes with full premium support. Essential Edition: Designed to give small businesses a quick and easy way to get started with a CRM system, this edition will give them everything they need. Its easy-to-use UI, intuitive tutorials, setup assistant, and administration tools will help you customize and scale your deployment over time. Essential Edition: Professional Edition: The Professional Edition is targeted at businesses that need full-featured CRM functionality to manage their operations. With Salesforce professional edition, businesses can conveniently manage their entire sales cycle from lead generation to close with ease. Professional Edition: Enterprise Edition: With the Enterprise edition, organizations can automate their complex business processes using workflows and approvals in addition to the features offered by the Professional edition. There are various customization and management tools included in this edition of Symphony to support large-scale deployments. Enterprise Edition: Unlimited Edition: A crucial feature of the Unlimited Edition is the ability to extend business success across the whole enterprise using the Lightning Platform so that the company can achieve maximum success. It offers all the features of the Enterprise edition and comes with full premium support. Unlimited Edition:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What are the different types of objects in Salesforce.com?",
        "answer": "Salesforce supports an extensive array of objects throughout its entire product lines, such as standard objects, custom objects, platform events, external objects, and BigObjects. Standard objects and custom objects are the two most common types of objects. Standard Objects: Standard objects in Salesforce provide a set of business objects. For example, Contact, Account, Opportunity, and Lead are all standard objects.\nCustom objects: A custom object is one that you can create to store data specific to your company or industry. Standard Objects: Standard objects in Salesforce provide a set of business objects. For example, Contact, Account, Opportunity, and Lead are all standard objects. Standard Objects: Custom objects: A custom object is one that you can create to store data specific to your company or industry. Custom objects:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. State difference between Salesforce.com and Force.com.",
        "answer": "  Salesforce.com: Salesforce.com is a CRM (Customer Relationship Management) service, based on SaaS (Software as a Service) technology.  Salesforce is a SaaS solution featuring Out of Box (OOB) functionality that allows a CRM system to automate marketing, sales, customer service tasks, etc. For instance, Google Apps, Dropbox, and GoToMeeting are examples of SaaS, and all refer to the process of taking software installed on your computer and transferring it to the cloud.\nForce.com: Force.com is a PaaS (Platform-as-a-Service) product that provides a platform for creating applications. In essence, Force.com is a platform that provides developers and business users with the means to develop powerful enterprise applications. The service allows you to customize the application, UI, and business logic. Salesforce.com: Salesforce.com is a CRM (Customer Relationship Management) service, based on SaaS (Software as a Service) technology.  Salesforce is a SaaS solution featuring Out of Box (OOB) functionality that allows a CRM system to automate marketing, sales, customer service tasks, etc. For instance, Google Apps, Dropbox, and GoToMeeting are examples of SaaS, and all refer to the process of taking software installed on your computer and transferring it to the cloud. Salesforce.com: Force.com: Force.com is a PaaS (Platform-as-a-Service) product that provides a platform for creating applications. In essence, Force.com is a platform that provides developers and business users with the means to develop powerful enterprise applications. The service allows you to customize the application, UI, and business logic. Force.com:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. How to delete or freeze users in Salesforce.com?",
        "answer": "There are some situations when you may not be able to deactivate an account right away, for example when a user has been selected in a custom hierarchy field. When deactivating users, it is recommended that you freeze their account to prevent them from logging in until you complete the steps to deactivate them. As an example, let us say that a user just left your company. Now, you wish to deactivate the account, but the user that you are selecting sits within a custom hierarchy field. It is not possible to deactivate the account immediately, but in the meantime, it can be frozen. Click Setup and then enter Users in the Quick Find box.\nClick on the username of the account you wish to freeze.\nClick on the button Freeze to lock down access to the account, or Unfreeze to enable it again, if necessary. Click Setup and then enter Users in the Quick Find box. Click on the username of the account you wish to freeze. Click on the button Freeze to lock down access to the account, or Unfreeze to enable it again, if necessary.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Explain PaaS.",
        "answer": "PaaS (Platform as a Service) is a proven model of running applications by leveraging cloud-based services without needing to worry about maintaining on-premises technology infrastructure and hardware. The simplicity, scalability, and reliability of PaaS solutions have been an important attribute for businesses of all sizes. The platform provides a set of cloud-based services that let business users and developers build applications at a pace not possible with on-premise solutions.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Explain SaaS.",
        "answer": "The term \"Software as a Service (or SaaS)\" refers to a way to deliver applications as a service over the Internet. As opposed to installing and maintaining software, you are simply accessing it via the Internet, thereby freeing yourself from the headache of software/hardware management. The SaaS model has since become a widely accepted model where more and more different types of applications are now available via the cloud.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Explain IaaS.",
        "answer": "The IaaS acronym stands for Infrastructure as a Service, which provides the basic computing resources (such as hardware, servers, networking components, etc.) for enterprises to deploy systems over the Internet. In addition to providing IT resources faster, such as troubleshooting and software upgrades, this service can also provide users with remote support. Furthermore, IaaS providers provide better security and data recovery than in-house systems do.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Can you explain the roll-up summary field?",
        "answer": "In a roll-up summary field, values from related records are calculated, for example, those from a related list.  It summarizes data from related detail records and displays it on the master record. There must be a master-detail relationship between the detail record and the master record.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. How to create a Roll-up summary field on the lookup relationship?",
        "answer": "You might prefer to aggregate child records on a parent record at times, but the Master-Detail capability may not align with your use case due to its security limitations. In such cases, it is best to use Flow Builder or write code to mimic the functionality of Roll-up Summary fields.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is a data loader?",
        "answer": "The Salesforce Data Loader is a client application that allows you to import or export data in bulk both to and from Salesforce. If you would like to insert, delete, update, or export Salesforce records, you can use this tool. Data Loader reads, extracts, and loads data from a database connection or CSV (Comma Separated Value) files when importing data. It exports data as CSV files.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. How to update, upsert, and export records using a data loader?",
        "answer": "Update:\nClick on the update button and login buttons with your credentials.\nNext, open the CSV file containing the updated data with the IDs, then select the object and complete the operation.\nUpsert:\nThe upsert function is the same as the update function, but here we can place new records as well.\nWe can insert new records and update existing records using this operation.\nExport:\nClick on the export button and then log in using your credentials.\nSelect the object you wish to export data from, specify the location in which you want to store this exported file, and then complete the operation. Update:\nClick on the update button and login buttons with your credentials.\nNext, open the CSV file containing the updated data with the IDs, then select the object and complete the operation. Update: Click on the update button and login buttons with your credentials.\nNext, open the CSV file containing the updated data with the IDs, then select the object and complete the operation. Click on the update button and login buttons with your credentials. Next, open the CSV file containing the updated data with the IDs, then select the object and complete the operation. Upsert:\nThe upsert function is the same as the update function, but here we can place new records as well.\nWe can insert new records and update existing records using this operation. Upsert: The upsert function is the same as the update function, but here we can place new records as well.\nWe can insert new records and update existing records using this operation. The upsert function is the same as the update function, but here we can place new records as well. We can insert new records and update existing records using this operation. Export:\nClick on the export button and then log in using your credentials.\nSelect the object you wish to export data from, specify the location in which you want to store this exported file, and then complete the operation. Export: Click on the export button and then log in using your credentials.\nSelect the object you wish to export data from, specify the location in which you want to store this exported file, and then complete the operation. Click on the export button and then log in using your credentials. Select the object you wish to export data from, specify the location in which you want to store this exported file, and then complete the operation.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Explain OWD (Organization-Wide Defaults). Can you tell me how many accesses are available in OWD?",
        "answer": "The term \"OWD\" stands for Organization-Wide Default, and this refers to the Baseline settings that determine what records can be accessed by which users and by what modes of access. By using sharing rules, you can override Organization-Wide Default settings. Different types of access are available in Organization-Wide Default as follows: Read/Write/Transfer\nPublic Read/Write\nPublic Read Only\nPrivate\nNo Access, View only, Use. Read/Write/Transfer Public Read/Write Public Read Only Private No Access, View only, Use.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What do you mean by sharing rules? Write its different types.",
        "answer": "For the users who do not own the records, sharing rules are used to alter the Organization-Wide Default settings in Salesforce to accommodate their needs. Sharing rules should be applied to objects whose OWD (Organization-wide defaults) are set to Public Read-only or Private, as sharing rules can extend the access but cannot inhibit the access provided by OWD. Using sharing rules, we can configure sharing access to be extended to users within public groups, roles, or territory boundaries. Using sharing rules, certain users are given greater access to your data by making automatic exceptions to your OWD. Types of Sharing Rules Types of Sharing Rules Account Sharing Rule\nAsset Sharing Rule\nContact Sharing Rule\nCampaign Sharing Rule\nData Privacy Sharing Rule\nOpportunity Sharing Rule\nLead Sharing Rule\nWork Type Sharing Rule, etc. Account Sharing Rule Asset Sharing Rule Contact Sharing Rule Campaign Sharing Rule Data Privacy Sharing Rule Opportunity Sharing Rule Lead Sharing Rule Work Type Sharing Rule, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What is workflow? Write workflow rule components in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "To streamline and save time across your organization's processes, workflows are a great way to automate routine chores and processes. Workflow rules are used to store and organize sets of workflow instructions in a comprehensible manner. In short, you can always summarize these instructions by putting them in an if/then statement. In the world of workflow rules, two major components can be found. Criteria: The \"if\" part of the \"if/then\" condition. It consists of conditions that, depending on their findings (true/fALSE), should cause the associated actions to occur.\nActions: The \"then\" part of the \"if/then\" condition. These are the actions that have to be taken if the criteria for workflow rules are met. Criteria: The \"if\" part of the \"if/then\" condition. It consists of conditions that, depending on their findings (true/fALSE), should cause the associated actions to occur. Criteria: Actions: The \"then\" part of the \"if/then\" condition. These are the actions that have to be taken if the criteria for workflow rules are met. Actions:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. Explain CRM (Custom Relationship Management). Write some CRM providers.",
        "answer": "Most of today's business people are familiar with the term CRM, which is an acronym for customer relationship management and is a tool for managing a company's relationship with its potential customers. There is a simple goal behind CRM, i.e., to build better relationships with clients. In other words, CRM systems make it possible for everyone to manage the external interactions and relationships that are the backbone of any successful business, including sales, business development, customer service, recruiting, marketing, and any other line of business. The CRM system enhances customer relations, streamlines processes, and improves profitability. List of CRM Providers List of CRM Providers Salesforce CRM\nSAP CRM\nSage CRM\nZoho CRM\nMicrosoft Dynamics CRM\nOracle CRM\nNetSuite CRM\nSugarCRM, etc. Salesforce CRM SAP CRM Sage CRM Zoho CRM Microsoft Dynamics CRM Oracle CRM NetSuite CRM SugarCRM, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Can you explain the custom metadata type?",
        "answer": "In Salesforce, Custom Metadata Types are a bit like Custom Settings, except they are customizable, deployable, upgradeable, and packageable. They are primarily used for application configuration. The first thing you need to do is create a custom metadata type that specifies the format and content of the application metadata. You can then create reusable functionality that determines behaviour based on the metadata of the type provided. Conclusion Job interviews can indeed pose a bit of a challenge, especially when proving your competency in the use of technology (logistics, computer skills, etc.). Salesforce is regarded as the world's best-known and most popular CRM platform, and there is a constant demand for Salesforce administrators in this day and age. As we have seen in this article, we have covered some likely Interview Questions you might encounter from the most commonly used topics in Salesforce administration. There are a lot of topics covered here like custom metadata type, differences between Salesforce.com and Force.com, ways to store files, images, and documents in Salesforce, different types of portals available in Salesforce, user administration, workflow components, types of reports, what a data loader is, and many more. In the end, you should realize that the aim is to provide a concise yet fully explained answer that demonstrates your knowledge of the subject without going on and on. It would be best if you could give an example of a use case you have experienced while using the feature. But, putting all of these aside, what is most important is a Salesforce Admin certification, since it is highly relevant in today's oversaturated market. As mentioned before, they aren't attempting to certify you, but rather gauge the degree of your expertise in the field. Also, be confident, professional, and courteous during the interview. Useful Resources https://www.interviewbit.com/blog/salesforce-developer-salary/\nhttps://www.interviewbit.com/salesforce-lightning-interview-questions/\nhttps://www.interviewbit.com/technical-interview-questions/ https://www.interviewbit.com/blog/salesforce-developer-salary/ https://www.interviewbit.com/blog/salesforce-developer-salary/ https://www.interviewbit.com/salesforce-lightning-interview-questions/ https://www.interviewbit.com/salesforce-lightning-interview-questions/ https://www.interviewbit.com/technical-interview-questions/ https://www.interviewbit.com/technical-interview-questions/",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What are the responsibilities of a Salesforce administrator?",
        "answer": "If you are a Salesforce Administrator, you would be the one who would bridge the gap between business people and technology specialists. You will work closely with key stakeholders to establish requirements, then you will customize Salesforce to meet those needs. The role is extremely varied, it entails both training other users, sharing best practices, and perfecting admin tasks, such as creating reports for clients, and ensuring that best practices are being followed. Salesforce administrators are responsible for all of the daily operations and user management of the CRM system.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. How do I prepare for the Salesforce interview?",
        "answer": "Here are some tips to help you prepare for a Salesforce interview: Make sure you prepare the basics.\nDo a bit of research and learn what the hiring manager is looking for.\nKeep notes of your achievements that might be of use to the hiring manager.\nResearch the company and the interviewer beforehand.\nDon't be afraid to speak your mind. Make sure you prepare the basics. Do a bit of research and learn what the hiring manager is looking for. Keep notes of your achievements that might be of use to the hiring manager. Research the company and the interviewer beforehand. Don't be afraid to speak your mind.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Why should we hire you?",
        "answer": "If you plan on applying for a position as a salesforce administrator, then you ought to look for the following skills. When you answer why you should be hired, highlight how these skills apply to you. Be committed to getting the job done.\nPossess additional experience (Sales, Analyst experience, Sales operation, or Marketing) that complements what is required in the position.\nHave experience with other CRM technologies besides Salesforce.\nLook for an internship or job as a fresh graduate to gain some experience in sales or with a CRM tool.\nCertification in Salesforce. Be committed to getting the job done. Possess additional experience (Sales, Analyst experience, Sales operation, or Marketing) that complements what is required in the position. Have experience with other CRM technologies besides Salesforce. Look for an internship or job as a fresh graduate to gain some experience in sales or with a CRM tool. Certification in Salesforce.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. How do I introduce myself in the Salesforce interview?",
        "answer": "There are a few important components that will enable you to answer the question in the best way. The following information should be included in your answer: Give them some insight into your professional background and personality, and explain who you are.\nMake sure to highlight the top three to five points about your career that you would like to convey.\nDo not forget to mention the companies you worked for, your roles, and your achievements.\nYou should spell out why you want this job and why you would be a good fit for it. Give them some insight into your professional background and personality, and explain who you are. Make sure to highlight the top three to five points about your career that you would like to convey. Do not forget to mention the companies you worked for, your roles, and your achievements. You should spell out why you want this job and why you would be a good fit for it.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is the salary of salesforce admin in India and U.S.?",
        "answer": "Mid-career Salesforce Administrators earn an average salary of ₹7.2 Lakhs per year, while senior Salesforce Administrators earn an average salary of ₹10.3 Lakhs per year. In the United States, a SalesForce Administrator earns an average salary of $91202 per year.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Is Salesforce administrator a good job?",
        "answer": "Increasingly, employers are looking for Salesforce professionals as they immerse themselves in the digital transformation process.  Salesforce administration is an excellent career to pursue since it is highly in demand. The main reason is that with a 19% share of the CRM market, Salesforce has become the world's leading Customer Relationship Management (CRM) platform. It's not only a highly respected and valued role in its own right, but it can also be a stepping stone into other career options within the ecosystem.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce-admin"
    }
]